Vanessa Carlinsia Tjong

West Jakarta 11510 | +62 855 8834 125 | carlinsiavanessa@gmail.com | Linkedin

PROFILE

Student from Bina Nusantara University majoring in Computer Science with strong academic foundation in software engineering. Experience in working with programming languages such as Java, Python, alongside web development technologies(HTML, CSS). Passionate on teamwork project and demonstrating a high level on responsibility. Motivated to apply academic knowledge and contributed to a software engineering internship.

EDUCATION

Bina Nusantara University

October 2022 - Present

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.43/4.00

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

TUTORAN

Design and Development team

- Collaborated in a team to design Tutoran using figma and develop Tutoran, a web platform for tutoring services.
- Implemented Agile methodology with scrum to enhance project management and improve team collaboration.
- Contributed to the design and development of user-friendly interfaces using Figma and features to enhance user experience.
- Engaged in regular problem-solving sessions with the team to identify and resolve project issues effectively.
- Participated in daily stand-up meetings to discuss progress, address challenges, and align on tasks.

WORK EXPERIENCE

I-Smart Bimbel

December 2022 – Present

Part-time teacher

- Teaching students varied from elementary school to middle school.
- Making teaching materials, exercises and answer sheets.
- Organizing and managing files on Google Drive.
- Provide educational support to students, facilitating learning and helping improve academic performance.

ORGANIZATION & VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Teach For Indonesia by Bina Nusantara University

May 2023 – June 2023

Volunteer Tutor

• Collaborated with other volunteer to create engaging lesson plans and facilitate effective learning experience.

Data Science Club 2023-2024

Activist in relation division (digital social marketing)

• Responsible to contributing on posting event announcements to the group, ensuring effective communication and engagement among members.

BNCC(Bina Nusantara Computer Club)

2022-2023

Member in UI/UX Design (LNT UI/UX)

• Learning in UI/UX design projects, learning and applying design principles using figma to create user-centered interfaces and enhance user experience.

St. Christopher 1 High School

Yearbook Committee

- Collaborated with a team to plan, design, meeting and publish the annual yearbook.
- Managing timelines, contributing with a creatives idea and ensuring the quality of the final product

Member of Student Council (OSIS)

- Participated in organizing school events and initiatives.
- Contributing to student management, community experience and fostering positive school environment.
- Collaborated with team to plan an event.

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- **Programming Languages:** HTML(Advanced), CSS(Advanced), Java(Intermediate), Python(Intermediate), PHP(Intermediate), C(Intermediate), C#(Basic), SQL(Basic)
- Operating Systems & Tools: Windows(Advanced), macOS(Intermediate)
- **Softwares & IDEs:** Microsoft Office(Advanced), Visual Studio Code(Intermediate), Eclipse(Intermediate), Dev C++ (Basic)
- Design Guideline Tools / Prototyping: Figma

Language:

- Bahasa Indonesia *Native*
- English *Proficient*
- Chinese Basic
- Korean Basic

Others

• Communication, Hardworking, Teamwork, Experience on working, Editing video and photos, Public Speaking, Problem Solving, Project Management.